CHRISTINE SCHATZ

CONTACT

- www.christineschatz.com
- **** 323-828-8487
- **♀** New York
- **y** theloopLA
- in linkedin.com/in/christineschatz
- ChristineSchatz

SUMMARY

I truly enjoy problem solving. Whether it's figuring out how an app's data should be structured or how a user experience should be designed, I'm energized by crafting creative solutions to problems. I'm drawn to passionate people who enjoy sharing ideas and making a difference. Fun fact: I'm a music blogger and former DJ.

EDUCATION

Northampton Community College

A.S. Computer Science 2015 Dean's List, GPA: 3.8

Dev Bootcamp

Full Stack Development 2015

University of California, San Diego

B.A. Visual Arts: Media 2009 Graduated with Honors

SKILLS

LANGUAGES: Ruby, JavaScript, Swift, Java, PHP,

Scala

FRAMEWORKS: Rails, Sinatra **TESTING:** RSpec, Capybara

FRONT END: HTML5, CSS3, Sass, Angular, jQuery,

React

METHODOLOGIES: Object-oriented design, Agile **DATABASE:** ActiveRecord, PostgreSQL, SQL

DEVOPS: Docker

EMPLOYMENT

Junior Developer (Contract) ValuePenguin New York, NY Oct 2015 to Dec 2015

- Built interactive tools such as a financial calculator
- Used JavaScript, React, jQuery, HTML5, CSS3, and Sass to build features on the front end
- Wrote Scala and PHP to customize data on the back end
- Developed in Docker containers

Web Editor & Coordinator - Entrepreneurship Program Lafayette College

Easton, PA Jul 2013 to Jun 2015

- Developed the footprints for an entrepreneurship initiative
 - Implemented JavaScript, HTML & CSS to departmental website
 - Worked with external partners & alumni to curate entrepreneurship-focused events

Project Analyst Knoll East Greenville, PA Jan 2013 to Jun 2013

- Compiled and analyzed data from supply chain work streams
- Created master project plan using project management software

Art Advisory Associate Isenberg & Associates Beverly Hills, CA 2010 to 2011

- Created presentations for public art events
- Maintained and edited website
- Corresponded with artists and clients during public project development

PROJECTS

the <hive>

A social networking site for software developers looking to collaborate on a side project. Users can coordinate meetups using an in-app messaging system. Users can also search for a project by any given city or zip code.

- Played a large role in implementing the Google Geocoding API to render location results.
- Designed the splash page
- Built a portion of the CRUD features for projects
- Implemented AJAX for smoother data loading

Stack: Ruby on Rails, JavaScript, jQuery, AJAX, Materialize, Sass

URL: https://code-hive.herokuapp.com

Emotional Baggage Check iOS app

The iOS app version of the popular desktop site Emotional Baggage Check. Users can post "baggage" anonymously as well as receive an anonymous response.

- Used Swift and Parse API as a backend
- Utilized MVC design pattern, divide and conquer strategies, and debugging tools throughout development

Stack: Swift, Objective-C, Parse

AWARDS

Style of Sound \cdot Best Music Blog Award

Oct 2014

Awarded ranking in Style of Sound's "Most Influential Music Blogs of 2014" list

ACTIVITIES

The Loop · Founder & Writer

Aug 2010 to Current

Music blogger for popular, Hype-Machine ranked music blog "The Loop." I work with PR agents and artists to feature independent music. I'm also a music reviewer for Fluence.io

Coders > Cancer Hackathon · Developer

Sep 2015 to Sep 2015

Collaborated on a team of 4 to develop Ladybug, a text messaging system that reminds women to do their monthly self breast exam. Used Ruby on Rails and HTML5, CSS3, and jQuery to design the splash page